Louis T. Michener Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Louis T. Michener Papers 1880-1927
MSS32813
Michener, Louis T. (Louis Theodore), 1848-1928
400 items
2 containers
.8 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lawyer, politician, and public official from Indiana. Correspondence, reports, memoranda, newspaper clippings, autograph album, and printed matter relating chiefly to Indiana and Republican Party politics and to Michener's role in Benjamin Harrison's senate and presidential campaigns.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927--Correspondence.; Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell), 1834-1928--Correspondence.; Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895--Correspondence.; Elkins, Stephen B. (Stephen Benton), 1841-1911--Correspondence.; Foraker, Joseph Benson, 1846-1917--Correspondence.; Gresham, Walter Quintin, 1832-1895--Correspondence.; Hanna, Marcus Alonzo, 1837-1904--Correspondence.; Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901--Correspondence.; Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901.; Hay, Eugene Gano, 1853-1933--Correspondence.; Manley, Joseph Homan, 1842-1905--Correspondence.; McKinley, William, 1843-1901--Correspondence.; Michener, Louis T. (Louis Theodore), 1848-1928.; Noble, John W. (John Willock), 1831-1912--Correspondence.; Payne, Henry C. (Henry Clay), 1843-1904--Correspondence.; Platt, Thomas Collier, 1833-1910--Correspondence.; Porter, Albert G. (Albert Gallatin), 1824-1897--Correspondence.; Robertson, Robert Stoddart, 1839-1936--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919--Correspondence.; Rusk, Jeremiah McLain, 1830-1893--Correspondence.; Sherman, John, 1823-1900--Correspondence.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930--Correspondence.; Wallace, Lew, 1827-1905--Correspondence.; Wanamaker, John, 1838-1922--Correspondence.
Organizations
Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); United States. Congress. Senate--Elections, 1886.
Subjects
Presidents--United States--Election--1888.; Presidents--United States--Election--1892.
Places
Indiana--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government--1865-1933.
Titles
Louis Theodore Michener papers
Occupations
Lawyers.; Politicians.; Public officials--Indiana.
Provenance
The papers of Louis T. Michener, lawyer, politician, and public official from Indiana, were purchased in 1931.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Louis T. Michener are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Louis Theodore Michener (1848-1928) span the years 1880-1927. The collection consists of correspondence, reports, memoranda, newspaper clippings, an autograph album, and printed matter relating chiefly to Indiana and Republican Party politics and to Michener's role in Benjamin Harrison's senate campaign of 1886 and presidential campaigns of 1888 and, 1892. Correspondents include Albert Jeremiah Beveridge, Chauncey M. Depew, Frederick Douglass, Stephen B. Elkins, Joseph Benson Foraker, Walter Quintin Gresham, Marcus Alonzo Hanna, Benjamin Harrison, Eugene Gano Hay, William McKinley, Joseph Homan Manley, John W. Noble, Henry C. Payne, Thomas Collier Platt, Albert G. Porter, Robert Robertson, Theodore Roosevelt, Jeremiah McLain Rusk, John Sherman, William H. Taft, Lew Wallace, and John Wanamaker.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is organized by type of material.
Container List
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Michener, Louis, 1880-1924, undated (Box 1)
  - Family, [1893?], July 27, undated (Box 1)
  - From Benjamin Harrison, 1881-1899 (Box 2)
  - From Theodore Roosevelt, 1884-1898 (Box 2)
  - From William McKinley, 1886-1900 (Box 2)
  - From William H. Taft, 1891-1912 (Box 2)
- Reports and memoranda (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, senatorial campaign of 1886 (Box 2)
  - Address to law class, 1887 (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, presidential campaign of 1888 (Box 2)
  - Biographical sketch of Walter Quintin Gresham, undated (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, presidential term, 1889-1893 (Box 2)
  - Presidential campaign, Republican national convention, 1892 (Box 2)
  - Chairman, Republican State Committee of Indiana, undated (Box 2)
  - Biographical sketches of Benjamin Harrison, undated (Box 2)
  - Memoranda, 1912, 1913, undated (Box 2)
  - Election forecast of 1923 (Box 2)
  - Dudley letter, undated (Box 2)
  - Comments on the work of Ferguson, undated (Box 2)
- Miscellany (Box 2)
  - Autograph album, 1892 (Box 2)
  - Printed matter, 1920 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1916-1927, undated (Box 2)
  - Typed clippings, 1910 (Box 2)